<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on DESUK: The Duke Ellington Society UK</title><link>http://dukeellington.org.uk/tags/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on DESUK: The Duke Ellington Society UK</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://dukeellington.org.uk/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wanted: New Editor</title><link>http://dukeellington.org.uk/2021/08/wanted-new-editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dukeellington.org.uk/2021/08/wanted-new-editor/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Patrick Olsen has stood down as a Committee Member and as Editor of Blue Light, a decision necessitated by changes in his professional life, including his recent move to Singapore. Blue Light has continued to thrive under his editorship, and it is important we express our gratitude to Patrick for all he has achieved on behalf of all members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even more important is our pressing need to find a successor. The forthcoming issue, 28-2, will be Patrick’s last. After that the Committee will take charge in the interim, but this arrangement can only be for the short term, and we do need a member to have editorial oversight of the activities involved. Without Blue Light DESUK as we know it would not survive for long, so the need is urgent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the various Blue Light activities, shared between the Editor and members of the Committee:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Themes, Balance and Range, Issue by Issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing copy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obtaining and preparing copy from other sources; securing permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sourcing and preparing pictures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events and DESUK activities: announcing and reporting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub-editing, checking factual accuracy, proof-reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page layout/production values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assembling page by page (currently 24 pages quarterly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converting assembled pages into a PDF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF to printer (currently Profile Business Supplies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collecting the finished product; stuffing envelopes and mailing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past the Editor has always been an officer or Committee member too, and there are obvious advantages in this, though my own view is that it need not be essential, as long as there exist good communications among the Blue Light team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also looking for offers of help in any one or more of the areas listed above. The future of BL will be more secure if the activities are shared among several members, working as a small team under the Editor’s guidance. That would have the advantage that the burden would not fall too heavily on one individual’s shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you feel you would like to become an Editor, or if you can contribute in any way to one or more aspects of producing Blue Light, or if you want to talk further about it, please get in touch with us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:desuk@dukeellington.org.uk&#34;&gt;desuk@dukeellington.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mailing list launched</title><link>http://dukeellington.org.uk/2020/08/mailing-list-launched/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dukeellington.org.uk/2020/08/mailing-list-launched/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To keep in touch with our membership in between issues of Blue Light, and to share news between issues, we have started an email mailing list. We will provide updates about mailings of Blue Light and other society events as and when they occur, and promise not to bombard our membership with excessive spam. The list is open to paid subscribers and the general public alike, and you can unsubscribe at any time. More details on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://dukeellington.org.uk/mailing_list/&#34;&gt;mailing list page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Twitter account launched</title><link>http://dukeellington.org.uk/2019/09/twitter-account-launched/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dukeellington.org.uk/2019/09/twitter-account-launched/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;DESUK is now on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dukesocuk&#34;&gt;@dukesocuk&lt;/a&gt;! Where better to start tweeting than &lt;em&gt;Flirtibird&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;DESUK&amp;#39;s first tweet! &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MpmRIFxYiJ&#34;&gt;https://t.co/MpmRIFxYiJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; DESUK (@dukesocuk) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dukesocuk/status/1171499295851175940?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;September 10, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dr John 1941 - 2019</title><link>http://dukeellington.org.uk/2019/06/dr-john-1941-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dukeellington.org.uk/2019/06/dr-john-1941-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dr._John&#34;&gt;Dr John&lt;/a&gt; (Malcolm John Rebennack Jr.) passed away on June 6, 2019. Among his extensive discography he leaves us an album of Ellington covers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.allmusic.com/album/duke-elegant-mw0000603953&#34;&gt;Duke Elegant&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun one. Check out an fascinating reworking of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DhCf8GSVsfM&#34;&gt;The Flaming Sword&lt;/a&gt; on the same album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/WSGgj088Skc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>